

# Yana Kotliar

UX/UI DESIGNER

New York City, NY (open for remote)

ykotliar.wd@gmail.com

682-205-0220

Yana Kotliar in

# TOOLS

Figma, Adobe XD Maze, Miro Basic understanding of CSS and HTML

## SKILLS

## Design

User-centered design, User research, Competitive analysis, Information Architecture, Wireframes, UI design, Visual Design, Branding, Low/Hi-Fidelity Prototyping, Mock-ups.

#### Research

User Interviews, User Surveys, Affinity Mapping, Journey Mapping, Competitive Analysis, User Personas, Card Sorting, Heuristic Evaluation, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, SWOT Analysis, Accessibility

## **Additional Skills**

Active listening, Communication, Interacting with customers, Resolving problems, Speaking 4 languages (Ukrainian, Russian - native; English, Polish - full professional proficiency)

## **PROFILE**

I'm a UX/UI Designer who's proficient in Figma, UX research, UX/UI design. I have a background in the economy, international relations, hospitality, and team management. My ultimate goal is to design simple, inspiring, and understandable products in order to create memorable user experiences

## RECENT PROJECTS

UX/UI designer

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022 Cook it- IOS mobile cook application.

Researched user needs and defined product goals by creating user stories and MVP. Applied research data to guide the user-centered design process. Created a functional prototype, ran usability tests. Designed a branding guide and logo and added design to the product.

November 2021 UX/UI designer

Portland electric - Client project, redesign for the current website. Collaborated with the client to define product requirements. Performed research including surveys, user interviews, and competitive analysis. Designed both mobile and web versions, branding, and updated the company's logo. Ran usability tests, and improved Hi-Fi prototypes based on feedback.

Sept- Oct 2021 UX/UI designer

On time - Public transportation application.

Using the Double diamond design system was conducting user surveys, research, determining the target audience, creating User personas, user flow, user stories, designing wireframes via Figma, creating a design system, Hi-Fidelity prototypes, running usability tests, writing usability test protocol.

**EDUCATION** 

09/2021 - 02/2022 **UX/UI Design Immersion Program, Certificate** - Thinkful 12 weeks long UX/UI program that is rooted in User Research

> fundamentals, Visual Design elements and principles, and accessibility through group workshops, one on one mentor sessions, and producing

professional projects.

06/2021 - 08/2021 Web design beginning, Certificate - Projector Institute

An online course that is focused on learning fundamentals and basic

principles of web design.

09/2015 - 06/2016 Mater of International relations - Vistula Academy, Warsaw, Pl

09/2011 - 06/2015 Bachelor of Economy - National Transport University, Kyiv, UA

# **EXPERIENCE**

05/2020 - 09/2021

Floor manager - LeCharlot, New York City, NY

Responsible for hiring staff, training team members through effective mentoring; problem-solved guest incidents or complaints

06/2018 - 03/2020

Manager - Emporio, New York City, NY

 Performed all duties associated with customer service; completed administrative duties within the timeframe given